campaignmonitor.com 2015-12-12

# The Campaign Monitor Privacy Policy | Campaign Monitor

At Campaign Monitor, we respect the privacy needs of our valued customers and members. This Privacy Policy outlines what specific information is gathered on the Campaign Monitor site and how that information is used.

Maintaining the privacy of your information is of paramount importance to us as it helps foster confidence, goodwill and stronger relationships with you, our customers. If, at any time, you have questions or concerns about our privacy practices, please feel free contact us at [info@campaignmonitor.com](mailto:info@campaignmonitor.com).

### Information Collection and Use

Campaign Monitor collects information that personally identifies you (“personal information”) in some circumstances, for example when you apply for our services or our customers provide your personal information to us so that we can help them communicate with you by email. The types of personal information we collect include name, contact details, identification information, organisation, title, information submitted in forms, payment details and enquiry/complaint details. We also collect personal information about your interactions and transactions with us, including any through monitoring and recording any contact we have with you by telephone, email or online for purposes including security, dispute resolution and training. We collect personal information directly from you as well as from third parties including public sources, our related companies, information service providers and the parties with whom we exchange information as described here.

We also store and manage information on behalf of our customers so they can manage their email campaigns. This includes information about our customers’ subscribers such as email addresses, emails received, links accessed (we sometimes track this for customers through our software) and other details entered by customers into our systems, which are subject to our Terms of Use but are not otherwise limited or controlled by us. It is possible that in this respect we could handle sensitive information such as information about professional association membership, political beliefs, health and religion. We do not use this information for our own purposes.

We collect, use and disclose your personal information to provide, administer, improve and personalise our products and services, maintain and update our records, manage our relationship with you and our customers and deal with your enquiries and concerns. We may also collect, use and disclose your personal information in connection with suspected fraud, misconduct and unlawful activity.

If you are our customer, your personal information is used to create your personal access to our email marketing product, and to contact you in the course of using this product. Financial information that is collected is used to verify, identity and to bill either you or your company for products and services, as applicable. Demographic and profile data collected by Campaign Monitor may be used to tailor this web site or any requested email communications, and to display information that is more relevant to you. Campaign Monitor also compiles demographic and product use information, but in the aggregate only, and may make that aggregate information publicly available. Under no circumstances will Campaign Monitor make any personal information about an individual user available publicly in this manner.

Your email address is used to only send you information that you have requested. As part of your use of our email marketing software, Campaign Monitor allows you to elect to receive, or not receive, certain information from Campaign Monitor. Campaign Monitor adheres strictly to permission-based email policy. Except as mentioned above, Campaign Monitor will not send you unsolicited email information, commercial offers or advertisements. Campaign Monitor will not sell, rent, or loan our contact lists or our customer’s contact lists (including customer data) to any outside firms not involved in the provision of Campaign Monitor services, nor will Campaign Monitor use customer contact lists for our own marketing purposes. All emails that you have requested will have an option to unsubscribe. Unsubscribe requests are fulfilled within minutes and no further communications will be sent to users who have stated that they do not wish to receive the specified information.

We may not be able to do the things described above without your personal information. For example, we may not be able to communicate with you and deal with your enquiries.

### Disclosure

Campaign Monitor will not use or disclose your personal information without your consent, except:

  * where required or authorised by law;
  * to implement the terms of any agreement we have with you;
  * to assist the lawful investigation of a law enforcement authority;
  * to protect the rights, property or personal safety of another Campaign Monitor customer, any member of the public or Campaign Monitor;
  * the assets and operations of the business are transferred to another party as a going concern; or
  * as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy.

We may exchange your personal information with our related bodies corporate, your representatives and with our service providers that assist us with archival, auditing, accounting, customer contact, legal, business consulting, banking, payment, delivery, data processing, data analysis, information broking, research, investigation, website or technology services. Third parties to whom we disclose personal information may be located in Australia, the United States of America and other countries.

### Subscriber Lists, Campaign Content and Campaign Reports

Campaign Monitor employs a range of measures to protect the privacy and confidentiality of personal information in subscriber lists, email content and reports. Campaign Monitor may scan the content of your campaigns to ensure it complies with our [Terms of Use](https://www.campaignmonitor.com/terms/) — to protect against defamatory, inaccurate, abusive, obscene, profane, or threatening material that is racially or ethnically offensive.

### Communications from the Site

#### Special Offers and Updates

We send all new users a welcoming email to verify their new account and confirm their password and username. Established users will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Customers can unsubscribe via the unsubscribe mechanism at the bottom of each email.

#### Newsletter

If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and email address. Out of respect for our users privacy we provide a way to opt-out of these communications via the unsubscribe mechanism at the bottom of each email.

#### Service Announcements

On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature.

#### Customer Service

We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account we reply via email or phone, in accordance with the user’s wishes.

### Website Usage Information

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our website. We do not link your IP address which accesses our website to any personal information. We use tracking information to determine which areas our site users visit based on traffic to those areas. Campaign Monitor does not track what individual users read, but rather how often each page is visited. This helps us maintain a superior and informative website for you.

Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to your computer's hard disk for record keeping purposes. Most web browsers are set to accept cookies. Campaign Monitor uses cookies to make your use of our website and services as convenient as possible. Cookies are useful to estimate our number of visitors and to determine overall traffic patterns through our website.

If you do not wish to receive any cookies you may set your browser to refuse cookies. This may mean you will not be able to take full advantage of Campaign Monitor's services.

In providing email campaign services for our customers, we may link cookies and IP addresses with records of emails received and links accessed to help our customers monitor the effectiveness of their email campaigns and manage their relationships with subscribers.

In some cases third parties may use cookies and other technologies such as web beacons and JavaScript on our website in connection with online services like website analytics and surveys. This may allow them to collect information about your use of our website (including your computer’s IP address) which they may store in the United States or other countries. The use of these technologies allows them to deliver customised evaluate users use of our website and other websites and provide other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Those third parties may also transfer the information they collect to others where required to do so by law, or where those others process the information on their behalf. The services we may use from time to time include Google Analytics, Yahoo, Adobe and Microsoft. You can find more details in the privacy policies for those services, including information on how to opt-out of certain conduct.

Our website may contains links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or policies of those sites.

### Security Technology

Campaign Monitor has made a substantial investment in server, database, backup and firewall technologies to protect our information assets. These technologies are deployed as part of sophisticated security architecture. All data resides in a tightly controlled, secure data center. These investments mean that information about the identity and preferences of individual members is strongly protected by Campaign Monitor against unauthorised access. We will maintain safeguards to protect the security of these servers and your personal information.

Campaign Monitor may process, store and back up its information with the assistance of those providers.

### Recruitment

If you apply for a position with us, we may also collect information about your experience, qualifications, skills, character and screening checks (including identity, eligibility to work, health, reference, background, directorship, financial probity, vocational suitability and criminal record checks). We collect, use and disclose your personal information to assess your application, conduct screening checks and consider and contact you about other positions. We may exchange your personal information with screening check providers, recruiters, academic institutions, health service providers, professional and trade associations, law enforcement agencies, referees and your current and previous employers. Without your personal information we may not be able to progress considering you for positions with us.

### Policy Modifications

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If/when Campaign Monitor makes changes to this privacy statement, we will highlight the changes on our homepage and email users who have given us permission to do so. We will post any changes here, so be sure to check back periodically.

### Contacting Campaign Monitor about Privacy

If you have any questions about our privacy statement, the information we have collected from you online, the practices of this website, or you wish to access or correct the personal information we hold about you, please contact us:

##### Postal Address

Campaign Monitor  
Level 38, 201 Elizabeth Street  
Sydney NSW 2000  
Australia

##### Telephone

+61 2 9521 5312

##### Fax

+61 2 9521 5316

##### Email

In the case of access and correction requests, please provide as much detail as you can about the particular information you seek, in order to help us locate it. We will comply with any applicable legal requirements to provide reasons if we deny any request for access or correction, or to make a requested note of your desired correction with the information.

We take your privacy concerns seriously. Where you express any concerns that we have interfered with your privacy, we will respond to let you know who will be handling your matter and when you can expect a further response.
